### Xinhu Li

CLVR Lab, Lira Lab Computer Science Department, USC

#### Research Interests

My ultimate research goal is to develop robust and generalizable agents that learn how to solve tasks in unstructured environments. To achieve this goal, I am particularly interested in the following:

- Utilize foundation models to boost generalization abilities across diverse tasks and environments.
- Develop self-adapting RL algorithms for minimal human oversight and autonomous decision-making.

Key Fields: Robotics, Reinforcement Learning, Machine Learning

#### EDUCATION

University of Southern California, Viterbi School of Engineering M.S. in Artificial Intelligence, GPA: 3.81/4	Aug. 2020 - Dec. 2022
Zhejiang University of Technology B.S. in Computer Science, GPA: 3.73/5 (top 5%)	Sept. 2016 - Jun. 2020

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

## Research Assistant, Lira Lab, University of Southern California

Oct. 2023 - Present

https://xhlsgit.github.io

lixinhu98@gmail.com

Advisor: Prof. Erdem Biyik, Prof. Joseph J. Lim

[Target: ICML 2024] **Xinhu Li\***, Ayush Jain\*, Zhaojing Yang, Joseph J. Lim, Erdem Biyik. "Beyond Policy Transfer: Self-Supervised Reward Adaptation"

- Introduced self-supervised reward adaptation for adapting policies without human assistance.
- Exceeds all other adaptation methods in manipulation and locomotion environment adaptation.

### Research Assistant, CLVR Lab, University of Southern California May 2022 - Oct. 2023 Advisor: Prof. Joseph J. Lim

[Submitted to ICLR 2024] Ayush Jain\*, Norio Kosaka\*, Xinhu Li, Kyung-Min Kim, Joseph J. Lim. "Rethinking Actor-Critic: Successive Actors for Critic Maximization."

- Proposed a successive actor-critic structure for effective max-action selection in actor-critic RL.
- Significantly improves the return in the minigrid, recommendation systems, and Mujoco-Gym.

# Research Assistant, Institute of Digital Media Technology, ZJUT Aug. 2019 - May 2020 Advisor: Prof. Meiyu Zhang

[Patent pending] Xinhu Li, Meiyu Zhang "Research and Implementation of Deep HDR Video Synthesis"

- Implemented LSTM for high-quality video synthesis from footage with varying exposure times.
- Enhances video quality substantially using a compact, efficient neural network.

# Research Assistant, MoE Key Lab of Network and Software Security Assurance, Peking University Jul. 2019 - Aug. 2019

#### Advisor: Prof. Zhong Chen

Aspect-based Sentiment Analysis (ABSA) with bi-LSTM structure

• Introduced bi-LSTM for ABSA, enhancing precision in sentiment component extraction.

• Enables generalization through whole content, improving extraction accuracy.

#### EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

#### Team Leader, ICPC Competition, Zhejiang University of Technology Jan. 2017 - Jan. 2020

- Demonstrated algorithmic skills by solving a set of algorithmic problems within a limited time frame.
- Achieves 16th rank in a national competition; detailed rewards under Achievements.

#### LEADERSHIP ACTIVITIES

Group Leader, Communication Club between Students and University Jan. 2016 - Jan. 2018

#### ACHIEVEMENTS

- Silver Award, China Collegiate Programming Contest, Final. (Rank 16)
- First Prize, Group Programming Ladder Tournament, China Collegiate Computing Contest
- Scholarship of Zhejiang Provincial Government (top 3%)
- Gold Award, The 2017 ACM-ICPC Asia Xi'an Regional Contest
- Silver Award, The 2017 ACM-ICPC Asia ShenYang Regional Contest
- Gold Award, China Collegiate Programming Contest, GuiLin
- Silver Award, China Collegiate Programming Contest, JiLin

#### Teaching

Teaching Assistant, Database Systems, USC (Prof. Sathyanaraya Raghavachary)

Spring 2022

- Developed course homework and held weekly office hours (four hours/week) for student support.

#### TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

- Robot Learning Proficiency: ROS, PyTorch, Tensorflow, Matplotlib
- English Proficiency:
  - TOEFL: Reading 26, Listening 26, Speaking 24, Writing 24
  - GRE: Quantitative: 170, Verbal: 156, Analytical Writing 3.5
- Programming Language: Python, JAVA, C++/ C, C#, R, SQL
- Relevant Courses: Robotics, Machine Learning, Deep Reinforcement Learning, Computational Human Robot Interaction, Linear Algebra